# Alyssa Sitto

https://alyssasitto.netlify.app https://github.com/alyssasitto
https://www.linkedin.com/in/alyssasitto www.youtube.com/channel/UCyFMoX6uULrgl3GHIZ OFnA alyssasitto1@gmail.com

I am a front-end focused web developer with extensive experience in building full-stack applications using React, Node, MongoDB, and Express. My expertise lies in designing and developing interactive user interfaces that provide an exceptional user experience. I pride myself in having a keen eye for detail and a deep understanding of modern web technologies.

#### SKILLS

• React

• Express

Node

MongoDB

• jQuery

• JavaScript (ES6)

• Git

CSS

• Responsive Design

## PROJECTS

Color Theme Visualizer <a href="https://theme-visualizer.netlify.app">https://theme-visualizer.netlify.app</a>

- A color theme visualizer that provides users with a way to experiment with different color combinations
- Built using React and Redux for state management
- Website allows users to use prebuilt color themes as well as add their own

#### Healthy Living <a href="https://healthy-living2.netlify.app">https://healthy-living2.netlify.app</a>

- Nutrition application that calculates the number of calories for users to lose, maintain, or gain weight based on their body dimensions
- The project was built using React for the frontend, Express for the backend, and MongoDB for the database
- Implements authorization and authentication with jsonwebtoken

#### **Spotify Clone** https://alyssas-spotify-clone.netlify.app

- Built using Spotify's REST API and Web Playback SDK
- Implements authentication and authorization through OAuth2.0 to ensure secure user access
- Project provides a seamless user experience that looks and feels very similar to the Spotify application

#### Cat Fishing https://alyssasitto.github.io/cat-fishing-game

- 2D game built using vanilla JavaScript, HTML, and CSS
- The functionality of the game was made possible with the use of canvas, allowing for the creation of a dynamic and visually appealing gaming experience
- The game's objective is to catch as many live fish as possible before coming into contact with a dead fish, at which point the game will end

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### Manicurist March 2021 – present

- Manage long list of clients. This includes making and scheduling appointments, keeping records, and maintaining relationships
- Build customer loyalty by providing excellent customer service and maintaining a positive attitude

#### Amazon Warehouse Associate Oct 2019 – March 2021

- Performed a number of tasks in fulfilling customer orders such as inspecting items for damage, picking, and packing
- Achieved a certain production rate each day, frequently recognized for being in the top 10% of associate production rates

#### Kohls Retail Associate Nov 2018 – Oct 2019

- Responsible for fulfilling online orders and completing them within a certain timeframe
- Maintained merchandise displays and strategically placed items in high traffic areas to increase sales

### **EDUCATION**

HIGH SCHOOL | Rivercrest Preparatory
FULL STACK WEB DEV BOOTCAMP | Ironhack

Graduation Year (2017)

Graduation Year (2022)